<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Olivier</title>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.alexolivier.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://blog.alexolivier.me</link>
    <description>Lover of technology, Editor of It's Kinda Cool, and follower of all sorts of geekery! Former Microsoftie, now startup Javascript guy at Qubit</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>My American Life - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.alexolivier.me/articles/my-american-life-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.alexolivier.me/articles/my-american-life-p1/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So having been here in New York for nearly a week now, there are a few things that I have noticed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s cold! It has been averaging around -5C here this week, and went down to -14C at its low point. My office is only 7 blocks away, but after about 3 I can’t feel my face, and this is with my ski jacket on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I already knew this one, TV here is awful, and I’m not just talking about the adverts. The production value of headline shows like Good Morning America is terrible. There is too much jumping around, and the audio levels are all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a startup at least, there is too much &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Valleyspeak&quot; title=&quot;Valleyspeak&quot;&gt;valleyspeak&lt;/a&gt;. It is like totally like cold out. And I think every sentence ends in a question?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I caught the end of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=arhBRouSmWs&quot;&gt;State of the Union&lt;/a&gt; where Obama did his stuff. As always I find American politics way too panderous and they really need quit the whole standing ovation thing every minute…also ‘God Bless America’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Omce the State of the Union had finished, the first thing one of the NBC (not even Fox!) commentators said ‘America needs to remember that Obama is only one letter away from one of the previous most wanted men in the world’…really?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Immigration at airports is not as stupid as it was - only one weird question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King_of_the_Nerds&quot;&gt;King of the Nerds&lt;/a&gt; is a program about some obviously clever people in a Big Brother-esque house who are deeply interested in their own particular areas, except sadly I know it is only getting viewers who laugh at these people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apparently there is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.superbowl.com/&quot; title=&quot;Superbowl&quot;&gt;some football game&lt;/a&gt; on this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Central Park in the snow is really nice to walk around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supermarkets are really expensive. Fast food is dirt cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every girl between about 16 and 25 wears boots, black leggings, body warmer, ear muffs and has a Starbucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The internet really does make the world smaller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I still love Mountain Dew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are plenty more things that I can’t think of at the moment, but this is going to be a series I think. Also, I am putting &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/photos/+AlexOlivierUK/albums/5973264711378523937&quot;&gt;photos up on my Google+&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start spreading the news...</title>
      <link>http://blog.alexolivier.me/articles/new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.alexolivier.me/articles/new-york/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 5 days, I am moving to New York! &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qubitproducts.com/&quot;&gt;Qubit&lt;/a&gt;, the startup I work for, currently has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qubitproducts.com/contact&quot;&gt;sales office in Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;, and I have being sent over there to setup the client engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will only be for a few months, but quite a scary prospect when I come to think of it. I will be responsible for doing technical pre-sales work, dealing our US clients, interviewing, hiring a training of engineers, aswell as keeping up with some of my current UK based clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for living, I’ve found a really nice one bed apartment near Union Square that is only 7 blocks from our office. This has been my first time using &lt;a href=&quot;http://airbnb.co.uk/&quot;&gt;AirBnB&lt;/a&gt; and so far the process has been OK - the first place I tried fell through, but hopefully this will all be sorted now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our CTO pointed out to me, this thing only really happens in startups…and I’ve only been at Qubit since August!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun times!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I will get the hang of this blogging thing....</title>
      <link>http://blog.alexolivier.me/articles/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.alexolivier.me/articles/hello-world/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog! I have tried to do this blogging so many times in the past, but never really got anywhere with it….lets see what happens this time!…maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>